Guide to the Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 185?-1953; Series I; 9.17; (23 boxes)
  - Letters by Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson to
    - Otis, A. H. (8140), [1889?] May 2 (Box 8, Folder 202)
      Includes note from Robert Louis Stevenson (8059)
    - Pinero, Arthur Wing, Sir (3723), 1911 March 30 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - R. & R. Clark (Firm) (8127), [1887 June 21] (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Rearden, T. H. (Timothy Henry) (8141-8152), 1874-1895 (Box 8, Folder 205)
      Contains typescript copies of letters, including letter by Robert Louis Stevenson (8063), and third party correspondence between Edwin J. Beinecke and J. C. Furnas
    - Robertson, Charles Grant, Sir (3724-3729), 1881-1886 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Sanchez, Nellie Van de Grift (3730), 1880 [September?]
    - Simpson, Evelyn Blantyre (8153), 1887 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Simpson, Walter, Sir (3731), 1884 January 22
    - Sitwell, Fanny (3732-3742 and 8154), 1884-[1895] (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Stevenson, Robert Louis (3743-3744 and 8155-8156), [1884, 1888] (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Stevenson, M. I. (Margaret Isabella) (3745-3812 and 8157-8161), [1880-1896] (Box 8, Folder 210-211)
    - Stevenson, Thomas (3813-3815), [1884 January] (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Stevenson, Thomas and Margaret (3618-3828), [1881-1886] (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Stoddard, Charles Warren (3829), [1904?] (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Storer, Mrs. (3830), [1897] April 20 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Strong, Austin (8162-8165), [1900]-1906 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Strong, Isobel Osbourne (3831-3832 and 8163-8181)
    - Thomas, Fred, Walter, and Frank (nephews) (3833), [1882 April] (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Williams, Dora Norton (3834-3897), [1875-1906] (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Unidentified (3898-3900), [1886-1895] (Box 8, Folder 219)
  - Letters to and about Robert Louis Stevenson
    - Adams, Henry (3901), 1891 February 6 (Box 8, Folder 220)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (3901)
    - André, Frédéric (3902), [1882-1883?] (Box 8, Folder 221)
      To: Thomas Stevenson (3902)
    - Angus, W. Craibe (3903), 1891 October 20 (Box 8, Folder 222)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (3903)
    - Archer, William (3904-3905 and 8182), 1888, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 223)
      To:
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (3904-3905)
      [John] Lane (8182)
    - Archibald, William (3906), 1906 June 12
      To: Sir Henry Stephen (3906)
    - Babington, Maud Wilson (3907 and 8183), 1895 January 25 (Box 8, Folder 224)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (3907 and 8183)
    - Baildon, Henry Bellyse (3908-3909), 1895
      To: Sidney Colvin (3908-3909)
    - Balfour, Henrietta (3910), 1887 May 7 (Box 8, Folder 225)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (3910)
    - Balfour, George W. (3911-3913), 1894-1895 (Box 9, Folder 226)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson
    - Balfour, Graham (3914-3942 and 8184-8189), 1887-1929 (Box 9, Folder 227-228b)
      Includes photostats of letters held in the Harvard College Library between Charles Baxter, Robert McClure, Mitchell & Baxter, and Stone & Kimball
      Sidney Colvin (3914-3922)
      Isobel Field (8188)
      Robert McClure (3923)
      Lloyd Osbourne (8184)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (3930-3938)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (3924-3928)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (3929)
      Charles Warren Stoddard (3939-3940)
      Austin Strong (3941 and 8185-8187)
      Lewis Henry Balfour Wilson (8189)
      Unidentified (3942)
    - Balfour, James (great-great grandfather) (8190-8193), undated (Box 9, Folder 229)
      Contains copies in an unidentified hand of letters written originally in 1729 and 1753
      James Balfour (8190-8192)
      David Hume (8183)
    - Balfour, Jane Whyte (3943-3946), 1894-1901 (Box 9, Folder 230)
      Mrs. Riggs (3943)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (3944-3945)
      Austin Strong (3946)
    - Balfour, Rev. Lewis (3947-3948), 1848-1850 (Box 9, Folder 231)
      To: Thomas Stevenson (3947-3948)
    - Balfour, Rhoda Brooke (8194-8195), 1925, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 232)
      To: Austin and Mary Strong (8194-8195)
    - Bangs, Lemuel W. (3949), 1893 June 9 (Box 9, Folder 233)
      To: Charles Baxter (3949)
    - Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew) (3950-3964), 1986-1907 (Box 9, Folder 234)
      Graham Balfour (3950)
      Lloyd Osbourne (3951)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (3952-3953)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (3954-3961)
      Austin Strong (3962-3964)
    - Baxter, Charles (3965-4059), 1875-1919 (Box 9, Folder 235-238)
      Grace Baxter (3965-3966)
      Sidney Colvin (3968-3976)
      W. Courthope Forman (3977)
      Lord Charles John Guthrie (3978)
      Thomas Hutchison (3979)
      John Lane (3980)
      Robert McClure (3981-3982)
      W. MacDonald MacKay (3987)
      Lloyd Osbourne (3988-3994)
      R. & R. Clark (3967)
      Sir Henry Stephen (3995-3997)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4053-4056)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (3998-4052)
      Herbert Stuart Stone (4057)
      Sir Herbert Beerbohm Tree (4058)
    - Baxter, Charles (3965-4059), 1875-1919 (Box 10, Folder 239-240)
    - Besant, Walter (4060), 1887 April 18 (Box 10, Folder 241)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4060)
    - Bigelow, Poultney (4061), 1892 November 7 (Box 10, Folder 242)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4061)
    - Bilton, L. Leonard (4062), 1927 March 15 (Box 10, Folder 243)
      To: unidentified (4062)
    - Bisset, A. (4063), 1873 March 20 (Box 10, Folder 244)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4063)
    - Black, Adam (4064), 1894 December 29 (Box 10, Folder 245)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4064)
    - Black, Louise (4065), [1894] December 28 (Box 10, Folder 246)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4065)
    - Blaikie, Walter Biggar (4066-4067 and 8196), 1899 August 28 (Box 10, Folder 247)
      Charles Baxter (4066)
      Lloyd Osbourne (4067)
      William Francis Prideaux (8196)
    - Bloomer, Hiram Reynolds (4068), 1890 December 3 (Box 10, Folder 248)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4068)
    - Boodle, Adelaide Anne (4069-4102 and 8199-8208), [1891]-1933 (Box 10, Folder 249-250)
      Rhoda Balfour (4069)
      Charles Baxter (4070)
      Charles Scribner's Sons (4071)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4076-4077)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4073-4075)
      Austin and Mary Strong (4078-4102)
    - Bowman, John (8209), 1950 August 14 (Box 10, Folder 251)
      To: Thomas Johnstone (8209)
    - Boyd, Julia (4103), 1891 October 20 (Box 10, Folder 252)
      To: Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4103)
    - Bradbury, Emelia Henrietta Balfour (5400), 1895 January 24 (Box 10, Folder 253)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (5400)
    - Brandeis, Judge (4104), 1892 December 15 (Box 10, Folder 254)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4104)
    - Branston, John (4105), 1893 April 15 (Box 10, Folder 255)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4105)
    - Brown, Horatio (4106), 1881 July 16 (Box 10, Folder 256)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4106)
    - Brown, John (4107-4108), 1879, [188-] (Box 10, Folder 257)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4108)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4107)
    - Bryce, W. (4109), 1893 May 2 (Box 10, Folder 258)
      To: Cassell & Company (4109)
    - Buchanan, Robert (4110-4111), [188-] (Box 10, Folder 259)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4110-4111)
    - Bunner, Henry Cuyler (4112 and 8210), 1887, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 260)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4112)
      Luther J. B. Lincoln (8210)
    - Burlingame, Edward L. (Edward Livermore) (4113-4156), 1887-1899 (Box 10, Folder 261)
      Sidney Colvin (4113-4116)
      Charles Scribner (4117)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4118-4156)
    - Burne-Jones, Edward (4903), [1885?] (Box 10, Folder 262)
      To: Sidney Colvin (4903)
    - Burney, C. D. (4157), 1892 December (Box 10, Folder 263)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4157)
    - Butler, William Allen (8211), 1894 December 20 (Box 10, Folder 264)
      To: Luther J. B. Lincoln (8211)
    - Cameron, John (4158), 1882 August 19 (Box 10, Folder 265)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4158)
    - Campbell, Alexander James Henry (4459), [189-] May 5 (Box 10, Folder 266)
      To: Charles Baxter (4459)
    - Campbell, Lewis (4159), 1885 January 30 (Box 10, Folder 267)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4159)
    - Cassell and Company (4160), 1899 May 23
      To: Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4160)
    - Cedercrantz, Conrad (4161), [1892?] April 16 (Box 10, Folder 268)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4161)
    - Chalmers, James (4162), 1891 August 8 (Box 10, Folder 269)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4162)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons
    - Charteris, A. H. (4163-4164), 1896 (Box 10, Folder 270)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4163-4164)
    - Chatfield, Robert T. (4165), 1896 July 15 (Box 10, Folder 271)
      To: Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4165)
    - Chatto, Andrew (8212), 1887 October 3 (Box 10, Folder 272)
      To: H. Buxton Forman (8212)
    - Chatto, Thomas (4166), 1895 January 16 (Box 10, Folder 273)
      To: unidentified (4166)
    - Cheney, Mrs. (4167), 1886 May 12 (Box 10, Folder 274)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4167)
    - Clarke, William E. (4168), [1894?] (Box 10, Folder 275)
      To: Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4168)
    - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne (4169), 1893 June 3 (Box 10, Folder 276)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4169)
    - Cobbe, Frances Power (4170), 1884 February 18 (Box 10, Folder 277)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4170)
    - Colley, C. Pomeroy (4171), [1885?] May 2 (Box 10, Folder 278)
      To: Henry James (4171)
    - Collier, John (4172), [1878] February 23 (Box 10, Folder 279)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4172)
    - Colvin, Sidney (4173-4417 and 8213-8218), 1873-1923 (Box 11, Folder 280-286)
      Includes three-volume compilation of correspondence between Colvin and Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson, Charles Baxter, Lloyd Osbourne, Edward Livermore Burlingame, Charles Warren Stoddard, and others relating to Colvin's editing of Stevenson's letters, as well as original letters by Robert Louis Stevenson. Also includes transcriptions for 4175-4271 and 4273-4316
      Graham Balfour (4173)
      Charles Scribner (4372)
      Cornelia E. Bamford (4174)
      Charles Baxter (4175-4336 and 8213)
      Edmund Gosse (8214-8216)
      John Hamer (4337)
      William Ernest Henley (4338)
      Mrs. Lang (4339)
      Lloyd Osbourne (4340-4370)
      Frank T. Sabin (4371)
      William Sharp (4373)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4405-4412)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4374-4386)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4387-4404)
      Charles Warren Stoddard (4413)
      Austin Strong (4414 and 8217-8218)
      John Walter Thomson (4415)
      Unidentified (4416-4417)
    - Crane, Walter (4418), 1879 April 24 (Box 11, Folder 287)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4418)
    - Crockett, Samuel Rutherford (4419-4428), 1887-1895 (Box 11, Folder 288)
      Lloyd Osbourne (4420)
      R. & R. Clark (4419)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4421-4428)
    - Croke, Wentworth A. (4429), 1891 May 21 (Box 11, Folder 289)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4429)
    - Cunningham, Alison (nanny) (4430-4436 and 8219-8220), 1897-1912 (Box 11, Folder 290)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4432-4435)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4430)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4431)
      Unidentified (4436)
    - Curin, P. W. (4437), 1893 April 18 (Box 11, Folder 291)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4437)
    - Curtiss, J. P. (4438), 1893 March 3 (Box 11, Folder 292)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4438)
    - Cusack-Smith, Thomas Berry (4439-4444), 1892-1894 (Box 11, Folder 293)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4444)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4439-4443)
    - Dalmette, C. (4445), undated (Box 11, Folder 294)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4445)
    - Damrosch, Walter Johannes (8220), 1894 December 21 (Box 11, Folder 295)
      To: Luther J. B. Lincoln (8220)
    - Daplyn, Alfred James (4446), 1892 September 22 (Box 11, Folder 296)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4446)
    - Derély, Victor (4447-4448), 1889 (Box 11, Folder 297)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4447-4448)
    - De Vere, Aubrey Thomas (4449-4450), 1887-1889 (Box 12, Folder 298)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4449-4450)
    - De Vinne, Theodore Low (4451), 1894 December 31 (Box 12, Folder 299)
      To: Luther J. B. Lincoln (4451)
    - Dick, James I. (4452-4453), 1888, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 300)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4452)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4453)
    - Dickens, Charles (8221), 1890 June 30 (Box 12, Folder 301)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (8221)
    - Dobson, Austin (8222), 1901 July 16 (Box 12, Folder 302)
      To: unidentified (8222)
    - Doxey, William (8223), 1896 July 3 (Box 12, Folder 303)
      To: Charles Scribner (8223)
    - Doyle, Arthur Conan, Sir (4454-4458), 1893-1896 (Box 12, Folder 304)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4454-4458)
    - Dunnstaffnage (4459)
    - Eeles, Charles G. S. (4460), 1894 December 22 (Box 12, Folder 305)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4460)
    - Eggleston, Edward (8224), 1895 January 4 (Box 12, Folder 306)
      To: Luther J. B. Lincoln (8224)
    - Fairchild, Charles S. (4461), 1887 September 3 (Box 12, Folder 307)
      To: Charles Scribner (4461)
    - Fairchild, L. N. (4462), [1890] December 24 (Box 12, Folder 308)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4462)
    - Fairfall, H. (4463), 1892 September 26 (Box 12, Folder 309)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4463)
    - Farrar, T. H. (8225), 1865 January (Box 12, Folder 310)
      To: David Stevenson (8225)
    - Fassett, B. (4464)
    - Ferme, Gertrude (4465), 1895 January 19 (Box 12, Folder 311)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4465)
    - Ferrier, Coggie (4466-4468), 1888-1895 (Box 12, Folder 312)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4467-4468)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4466)
    - Ferrier, Mrs. M. L. (4469), [1883?] February 14 (Box 12, Folder 313)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4469)
    - Field, Isobel (5807-5824 and 8306-8315), 1887-1896 (Box 12, Folder 314-316)
      Jane Whyte Balfour (5807-5808)
      Warren Howell (8306)
      Annie H. Ide (8307)
      Edith Livermore (8308)
      James Hilary Mulligan (8309)
      Eben Plympton (8310)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (5809-5821)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (5822)
      Charles Warren Stoddard (8311-8313)
      J[ohn?] W[alter?] Thomson (8314)
      Dora Norton Williams (5823)
      Unidentified (5824)
    - Fowler, William (4470), 1922 December 22
      To: Sidney Colvin (4470)
    - [Fowke Case], 1897 (Box 12, Folder 317-318)
      Includes notes and clippings
    - Galpin, Thomas D. (4471), 1886 February 16 (Box 12, Folder 319)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4471)
    - Garrard, Charles W. (4472), 1882 April 5 (Box 12, Folder 320)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4472)
    - Garschine, Sophie (4473), 1874 May 7 (Box 12, Folder 321)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4473)
    - Gilder, Joseph Benson (4474), [1888] March 25 (Box 12, Folder 322)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4474)
    - Gilder, Richard Watson (4475), 1886 February 3 (Box 12, Folder 323)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4475)
    - Godkin, Edwin Lawrence (8227), 1894 December 22 (Box 12, Folder 324)
      To: Luther J. B. Lincoln (8227)
    - Gosse, Edmund William (4476-4486), 1883-1885 (Box 12, Folder 325)
      Richard Watson Gilder (4476-4485)
      William Ernest Henley (4486)
    - Graham, Ernest (4487), 1886 August 31 (Box 12, Folder 326)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4487)
    - Grant, Robert (8228), 1894 December 24 (Box 12, Folder 327)
      To: Luther J. B. Lincoln (8228)
    - Green, Roger Lancelyn (8229), 1948 May 19 (Box 12, Folder 328)
      To: Isobel Field (8229)
    - Greene, Jane Whytt Elizabeth Anne Wilson (4488), 1895 January 24 (Box 12, Folder 329)
      To: Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4488)
    - Greenhill, Edmund H. (4489), 1886 August 23 (Box 12, Folder 330)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4489)
    - Greenwood, Frederick (4490), [1876] November 4 (Box 12, Folder 331)
      To: Sir Leslie Stephen (4490)
    - Grey, George, Sir (4491-4492), 1893-1894 (Box 12, Folder 332)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4491-4492)
    - Hackett, A. R. (4493), [1882] (Box 12, Folder 333)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4493)
    - Haggard, Bazett Michael (4494), [189-] (Box 12, Folder 334)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4494)
    - Haggard, H. Rider (Henry Rider) (4495-4497), [188-] April 30 (Box 12, Folder 335)
      Andrew Lang (4495)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4496-4497)
    - Hamer, John (4498-4503), 1893 (Box 12, Folder 336)
      Charles Baxter (4498-4499)
      Sidney Colvin (4500-4503)
    - Hamerton, Philip Gilbert (4504-4523), 1875-1887 (Box 12, Folder 337)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4504-4520)
      Thomas Stevenson (4521-4522)
      Unidentified (4523)
    - Hamilton, John D. (8230-8231), 1923
      To: Sidney Colvin (8230-8231)
    - Hammond, Basil (4524-4526), 1883, 1886 (Box 12, Folder 338)
      To: Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4524-4526)
    - Hardy, Thomas (4527), 1922 November 10 (Box 12, Folder 339)
      To: Rosalind Orme Masson (4527)
    - Hare, John Fairs (4528), [1884 November] (Box 12, Folder 340)
      To: William Ernest Henley (4528)
    - Harper and Brothers (4529), 1887 March 11 (Box 12, Folder 341)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4529)
    - Harrison, Virginia B. (8232), 1887 January 31 (Box 12, Folder 342)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (8232)
    - Hart, John (4530), 1889 August 12 (Box 12, Folder 343)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4530)
    - Heisch, C.E. (4531), 1886 March 2 (Box 12, Folder 344)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4531)
    - Hellman, George S. (George Sidney) (8233), 1925-1945 (Box 12, Folder 345)
      Includes third party correspondence between Hellman and others relating chiefly to his work The True Stevenson
    - Henderson, Daniel McIntyre (4532-4534), 1895 February (Box 12, Folder 346)
      To: Charles Warren Stoaddard (4532-4534)
    - Henderson, George J. (4535), 1886 March 5 (Box 12, Folder 347)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4535)
    - Henderson, James (4536), 1885 March 17 (Box 12, Folder 348)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4536)
    - Henley, Anna Boyle (4537-4539), [1884]-1911 (Box 12, Folder 349)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4538-4539)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4537)
    - Henley, William Ernest (4540-4893 and 8234-8236), 1875-1900 (Box 13, Folder 350-358)
      Lemuel W. Bangs (4540)
      Charles Baxter (4541-4648)
      Grace Baxter (4649)
      Robert Hamilton Bruce (4650-4664)
      Andrew Chatto (4665-4668)
      Sidney Colvin (4669-4672 and 8234-8235)
      Katharine de Mattos (4673-4678)
      Alfred Trübner Nutt (4679-4689)
      Sir Leslie Stephen (4690)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4880-4891)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4691-4692)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4693-4879)
      Thomas Stevenson (8236
      Algernon Charles Swinburne (4892)
      Unidentified (4893)
    - Henley, William Ernest (4540-4893 and 8234-8236), 1875-1900 (Box 14, Folder 359-369)
    - Herbert, Auberon (4849), 1888 August 16 (Box 15, Folder 370)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4849)
    - Hole, William B. (4895-4898), [1886-1890] (Box 15, Folder 371)
      Lloyd Osbourne (4895)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4896-4898)
    - Howells, William Dean (4899 and 8237), 1893 September 13 (Box 15, Folder 372)
      William Dean Howells (8237)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4899)
    - Hume, David (copy) (8238), undated (Box 15, Folder 373)
      To: James Balfour (8238)
    - Hutchinson, Allen (8239-8240), 1900-1901 (Box 15, Folder 374)
      To: Frederick Smith (8239-8240)
    - Hutton, Laurence (8241), 1894 December 20 (Box 15, Folder 375)
      To: Luther J. B. Lincoln (8241)
    - Huxley, Leonard (8242), 1925 February 18 (Box 15, Folder 376)
      To: Adelaide Anne Boodle (8242)
    - Ide, Annie H. (8243), [1891?]
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (8243)
    - Ide, Henry C. (4900-4901), [1891], 1894 (Box 15, Folder 377)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4900-4901)
    - Ionides, C. A. (4902), 1884 January 27 (Box 15, Folder 378)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4902)
    - J., E. B. (4903), [1885?]
    - Jack, James (8244), 1887 August 20 (Box 15, Folder 379)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (8244)
    - Jacobs, Joseph (4904), 1893 August 22 (Box 15, Folder 380)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4904)
    - James, Henry (4905-4965), [1884]-1898 (Box 15, Folder 381-388)
      Sidney Colvin (4905-4917)
      Isobel Field (4964-4965)
      Edmund Gosse (4918)
      Lloyd Osbourne (4919)
      Fanny Sitwell (4920)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4957-4963)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4921-4956)
    - James, Margaret (8246), 1917 June 14 (Box 15, Folder 389)
      To: Isobel Field (8246)
    - Japp, Alexander Hay (4966), 1901 August 31 (Box 15, Folder 390)
      To: Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4966)
    - Jenkin, Anne Austin (4967-4981), 1879-1910 (Box 15, Folder 391)
      Charles Scribner's Sons (4968-4974)
      Katharine Durham Osbourne (4967)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (4975)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4976-4980)
      Austin Strong (4981)
    - Jenkin, C. Frewin (4982), 1887 August 9 (Box 15, Folder 392)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4982)
    - Jenkin, Fleeming (4983-5000), 1879-1885 (Box 16, Folder 393-394)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (4999-5000)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (4983-4998)
    - Jersey, Countess of (Child-Villiers, Margaret Elizabeth Leigh) (5001-5004), 1892-1895 (Box 16, Folder 395)
      Margaret Isabella Stevenson (5001)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (5002-5004)
    - Jersey, Earl of (Child-Villiers, Victor Albert George) (5005-5008), 1893-1895 (Box 16, Folder 396)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (5008)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (5005-5007)
    - Johnston, George P. (5009-5010), 1893-1894 (Box 16, Folder 397)
      To: Charles Baxter (5009-5010)
    - Jones, Henry Arthur (5011-5012), 1885, 1887 (Box 16, Folder 398)
      William Ernest Henley (5011)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (5012)
    - Jowett, Benjamin (4464), 1886 April 16 (Box 16, Folder 399)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (4464)
    - Kaiulani (Princess of Hawaii) (5013), 1889 August 17 (Box 16, Folder 400)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (5013)
    - Kalakua (King of Hawaii) (5014), [1889 April] (Box 16, Folder 401)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (5014)
    - Kelley, J. D. Jerrold (James Douglas Jerrold) (5015), 1887 September 15 (Box 16, Folder 401a)
      To: Charles Scribner (5015)
    - King, W. J. (5016), 1892 July 20 (Box 16, Folder 401b)
      To: Lloyd Osbourne (5016)
    - Kingsley, Rose G. (5017), 1885 November 17 (Box 16, Folder 401c)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (5017)
    - Lang, Andrew (5018-5131), [1874-1895] (Box 16, Folder 402-407)
      Andrew Lang (5018-5022)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (5128-5131)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (5023-5127)
    - Leigh, John George (5132), 1900 March 23 (Box 16, Folder 408)
      To: Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (5132)
    - Lieght, George H. (8248), 1887 June 30 (Box 16, Folder 409)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (8248)
    - Locker-Lampson, Frederick (5133-5134), 1886-1893 (Box 16, Folder 410)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (5133-5134)
    - Longman, Charles James (5135-5138), 1885-1893 (Box 16, Folder 411)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (5135-5138)
    - Low, Will Hicok (5139-5170 and 8249-8250), 1883-1924 (Box 16, Folder 412-413)
      George S. Hellman (8249-8250)
      William Ernest Henley (5139)
      Luther J. B. Lincoln (5140)
      Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (5170)
      Robert Louis Stevenson (5141-5169)
    - Maben, Thomas (5171), 1893 April 28 (Box 17, Folder 414)
      To: Robert Louis Stevenson (5171)